[The Heir]
[Episode 5]
Grandfather,
please teach me how to make ink.
Zhen,
I have sworn an oath that,
from now on,
I'll never involve myself
in ink-making again.
Just give up on this.
You only swore never to make ink,
but you didn't say
you wouldn't teach others.
No means no.
There's no use saying more.
Zhen,
don't be stubborn with your grandfather.
Our family has suffered misfortunes
all these years,
all because of this ink.
Your father died because of ink.
Your grandfather suffered
worse than death because of it.
It also ruined the marriages
and future of you and your brother.
Hasn't ink harmed our family enough?
That's right.
Mother,
our family has hit rock bottom,
all because of ink.
Therefore,
I must earn
it all back through ink.
Earn it all back?
What do you have to earn it back?
How can you do it?
I suggest you
give up this idea now.
I will absolutely not agree to it!
I want to live with my head held high!
As for the ink-making,
I have made up my mind!
Even if Grandfather won't teach me,
I will go to other workshops to learn.
I must make a mark out there!
Zhen.
Are you sure this will work?
It will.
Zhengliang, don't worry.
I've asked around.
Every ink workshop is hiring new recruits.
I should try them one by one.
Which ink workshop do you plan to go to?
Third Grandfather's place, of course.
The Chen's Ink Workshop.
What if you get discovered?
It's fine.
I'll go first
and deal with it if I'm discovered.
Besides,
even if Third Grandfather discovers me,
he can't do anything to me.
Remember,
you must help me hide this from Mother
and never let her know.
If Mother finds out about it,
she will definitely tear me apart.
Zhen,
this is a new set of clothes
Ms. Du made for me.
I haven't even worn them yet.
Don't ruin them.
I see.
Zhengliang, remember
to keep it from Mother.
I'm leaving.
Be careful!
[Chen's Ink Workshop]
Starting today,
you will pound ink here.
No running around.
If you break the rules, you leave.
You go pound at the back.
Okay.
You
use this pestle to pound.
You three,
go pound over there.
Master,
how many times do we have to pound this?
A hundred thousand times for light glue.
Just focus on pounding.
Someone will come to check it later.
Lin!
Bring the ink blocks
and distribute them.
[Win Laurels in the Golden Palace]
Third Master,
we recently hired a new worker
to pound ink.
But the more I look at her,
the more she looks like
Eighth Master Li's granddaughter.
Where is she?
That's her over there.
She works pretty hard
and looks sharp-witted, too.
Should we
[Third Master Chen, Chen Jiru,
Manager of Chen Ink]
keep her or not?
The ink workshop recruits
and keeps anyone who can work.
Okay.
Send her to the smoke shed to burn soot.
Jinshui,
we two brothers
haven't had a drink together
for a long time.
Cheers.
You invited me for a drink
out of the blue.
Tell me.
What's the matter?
I was afraid you'd be bored
not making ink,
so I came to chat with you.
Come on, eat up.
Come on.
What has your granddaughter, Zhen,
been busy with lately?
She's working at Mr. Shui's food stall.
She goes out early
and comes back late every day.
You saw it?
What do you mean?
Just say whatever you want to say.
Jinshui.
I have something to tell you.
You can't get mad when I say it.
If you do, I just won't say it.
Then I won't get mad.
Go ahead.
Zhen...
She is now
working in my ink workshop.
Then why didn't you stop her?
Look, look.
You promised not to get mad.
Hear me out.
I think Zhen is quite a good girl.
She's smart,
and she works hard.
Just as the old sayings go,
like father, like daughter;
the apple doesn't fall far from the tree.
I already noticed she had a talent
for learning ink-making
when she was little.
Cut it out.
I don't care what your son does.
But Zhen cannot do it.
Why did you get worked up
just from talking?
Don't regret it
when I finish teaching her.
Chen the Third,
kick Zhen out of your ink workshop.
Otherwise, we are no longer brothers.
The young one is stubborn,
but the old one is even more so.
[Luo's Ink Workshop]
Working anywhere is the same
as long as I can make ink
and learn the craft.
Master Zeng,
we've taken in
a new batch of apprentices recently.
Please take a look.
[Zeng Yipin, Ink-making Master of Luo Ink]
Pounding ink requires strength.
Other ink workers are
all wearing undershirts.
Why aren't you wearing one?
I'm not hot.
So there's no need.
Is it that you don't need it,
or you can't wear it?
I don't n-need it.
You...
What are you doing?
So you are indeed a girl.
Women cannot make ink.
How dare you violate the industry rules
and ruin the reputation of our Luo family?
Who says women can't make ink?
That's just word of mouth.
Which book
records a written rule,
saying that women can't make ink?
What a sharp-tongued girl.
You broke the rules
and still talked tough.
Fine.
Then come with me
to the Literary Association
and sort this out properly.
Guards!
Take this girl
and come with me.
What? Don't touch me!
I can walk by myself!
President Hu,
and all the Heads of the Houses
in the ink industry,
today,
please judge it for my Luo family.
This girl disguised herself as a man
and snuck into the Luo's Ink Workshop.
She ruined the family's tradition
and disgraced the industry.
-This is outrageous.
-What a shame.
I only found out today
that you, Zeng Yipin,
can already represent the Luo family
to handle things.
Eldest Young Master,
I have worked for Luo Ink for years,
so, of course, I share the honor
and disgrace of the Luo family.
Share the honor and disgrace?
Li Zhen!
You are a woman.
How could you disguise yourself as a man
and sneak into the ink workshop?
How inappropriate!
You've been such a disgrace
to the Li family!
Uncle Jingdong, you really are forgetful.
I've long been expelled from the clan.
Even if I'm a disgrace,
what does it have to do
with your Li family?
Enough.
Since you are here
at the Literary Association to argue,
the Literary Association
will help you settle this.
President Hu,
our Huizhou ink industry
has always had a rule
that women cannot make ink.
That is merely an old cliche
passed down by word of mouth,
but not a written conclusion.
How can it serve as a constraint?
I've heard
that Aunt Luo Mengzhen
of the Luo family had astonishing talent
in ink-making.
The ink-blending technique
still used by Luo Ink today was
just invented by Aunt Luo.
I have a question for you, Master Zeng.
Since you've worked
for Luo Ink for so many years,
have you ever used
the Luo family's ink-blending technique?
Well...
Since you have used it,
using a technique created by a woman
while blatantly
claiming that women cannot make ink
is truly contradictory
and ungrateful.
Miss Li, I know you are
an expert at identifying pine and ink.
Not until today did I learn
that you're also this sharp-tongued.
That "ungrateful" comment
was really well said.
I think
ink-making
is about talent.
As long as one can make good ink,
who cares if it's a man or a woman,
a person or a dog?
Every family has its rules,
and every trade has its regulations.
If even random nobodies could make ink,
wouldn't our Huizhou ink industry
be turned upside down?
Are you worried that you lack talent
and can't even beat
these "random nobodies"?
Eldest Young Master Luo,
please mind your words.
How can you compare me to her?
I am the orthodox ink-maker!
What is "orthodox"?
Making good ink is orthodox.
Failing to make good ink
is disappointing one's ancestors!
You.
Tell me
how the ink made by Miss Li is.
Eldest Young Master,
I heard
that she did learn
how to melt glue pretty well.
That's an honest comment.
Miss Li
also came to the Pan's Ink Workshop.
The master said
[Pan Yongnian, Manager of the Pan family]
she was not very good
at woodblock printing,
but she worked really hard.
Miss Li,
please stretch out your left hand.
It's fine.
Just show them.
Open it and hold it high.
Higher.
Everyone here is an expert in ink-making.
If you want to know whether a person
is truly sincere about ink
or just faking it,
it's all in their hands.
Look carefully!
I guess you've been rich for so long
that your hands have been blessed,
lost their calluses,
and grown new flesh, huh?
Since Eldest Young Master Luo said so,
if I stick to the word of mouth that women
cannot make ink,
wouldn't I seem pedantic?
It's just that
our ink industry only passes skills
to men, not women.
This is actually because women
will eventually marry someone,
and the ink recipe cannot
fall into the hands of other families.
Previously,
the Li family's ink recipe was
almost leaked.
Regarding Miss Li Zhen
breaking off her engagement in public,
I suppose
you all
know it.
President Hu,
my learning to make ink
has nothing to do with Li Ink.
How could the ink recipe be leaked?
If anyone here is worried,
I can just swear an oath
that I will never marry anyone.
Well...
Miss Li,
it is wrong for you to say so.
If so,
Eighth Master Li
will definitely blame us.
Third Master.
Everyone,
after all,
Li the Eighth is the head
of the Five Ink-making Grandmasters.
He has contributed a lot to Hui Ink.
Even though he has quit
mading ink for a long time,
we shouldn't forget what he's done for us.
Today,
if we make things difficult
for his granddaughter like this,
I think everyone here
would feel bad about it.
Why don't we just
give Miss Li Zhen a chance?
She has learned to make ink for a while.
We might as well let her
make an ink stick.
Well...
Then,
we can all
take a look and evaluate it together.
If Miss Li Zhen
truly has a gift for making ink,
the ink industry
should not let such a talent go to waste.
Third Master,
you've got a point.
Miss Li Zhen,
do you accept it?
She disguised herself as a man
to sneak into various major ink workshops.
How shameful!
As her older brother,
why didn't you stop her?
You...
You've really grown some nerve!
You're getting bolder and bolder!
You're really pissing me off!
Zhen did that
to learn ink-making and earn more money
to support our family.
Our family doesn't need to rely on her
to make a living!
Mother,
just let Zhen do it.
If she really fails in the end,
she won't blame us.
If we stop her,
and she gets angry,
who knows what she will do?
That would be even worse.
This girl
from the Li family
actually had no shame
and went to work at an ink workshop!
She made such a big scene,
causing all my peers to laugh at me.
Ronghua.
Come down here.
I have something to tell you.
Sit down.
Ronghua,
from now on,
don't get mixed up with that crazy girl
from the Li family
anymore.
A woman's reputation
matters so much!
Besides,
I
have arranged a marriage for you.
Just stay at home.
Don't ruin it
because of her.
Marriage?
Father,
Mother,
w-why didn't I know about this engagement?
It's just right that you don't know.
Since ancient times,
children's marriages
have always been
determined by their parents
and matchmakers.
For Eldest Young Master Luo
becoming related
with our Tian family by marriage,
we are already climbing above our station.
You should be happy about it.
Father,
well,
you know Eldest Young Master Luo's temper
better than I do.
Besides...
Besides, he already had a wife
and concubines.
I don't want to marry him.
You have to marry him
whether you want to or not.
Look,
just because she's spent too much time
with that girl from the Li family,
now she can even say such words
against filial piety.
Mother,
I don't want to leave you and Father yet.
Besides, I've never spent time
with Eldest Young Master Luo.
I don't want to leave my fate
in the hands of a stranger like him.
Did you hear that?
What on earth were you saying?
Why are you
throwing such a temper tantrum?
If you have something to say,
talk to her nicely.
She will understand.
Shut up.
All you do is spoil the children.
Look at the 3 children of our Tian family.
Each of them is a hard nut to crack.
This matter is settled, then.
For the sake of our Tian family,
just be good and stay at home.
If you dare to have thoughts
like Li Zhen's
and want to call off the engagement,
I'll break your legs!
Master.
A bunch of goof-got-nothings.
Ronghua, how do you have time
to visit me today?
Zhen,
my marriage has been arranged.
That's a good thing
to have your marriage arranged!
Which young master is so lucky?
It's...
Eldest Young Master Luo.
Luo Wensong?
He is
so old
and also eccentric in personality.
Besides,
he is taking a second wife.
The Luo family is so prominent.
Many girls would be
willing even to be his second wife.
Speaking of this,
it's me who climbs above my station,
marrying Eldest Young Master Luo.
My father said that,
in a few days,
he will go dig a well for the Luo family.
[Cave Digging:
In Huizhou, before a girl gets married,]
[her natal family should go
to dig a well in her husband's house,]
[implying that after marriage,
her natal family will cover her expenses.]
Ronghua,
[This is the marriage tradition
in ancient Huizhou.]
do you
like Eldest Young Master Luo?
Marriages are decided
by parents and matchmakers.
Whether I like him or not
doesn't matter.
Alright.
They say
older men are more caring.
Perhaps
it'll be a good marriage.
Enough about this.
Zhen,
I came today
to give you something.
What is this?
Zhen, I know
you will need these since you've
started learning ink-making.
I took these
from my family's ink workshop.
Use them for now.
Otherwise, you'd have to buy them.
Ronghua,
these gold foil
and pearls are way too precious.
I can't take them.
If your family finds out,
you'll be in trouble, I'm afraid.
Don't worry.
I didn't take much.
It's fine.
Take them,
and consider
that I, Tian Ronghua,
contribute a bit to the ink you make.
From now on,
you can help me do the things
that I can't do.
Father,
thanks to Third Grandfather Chen
for lending me his ink workshop,
I spent quite a lot of time
managing to make this only piece
of fairly good-quality ink stick.
Father,
you must bless me to succeed
in the ink assessment.
The ink is grayish,
and it feels too sluggish.
It's still not good enough.
What exactly went wrong here?
Show me
what kind of ink you made.
Don't look.
The ink hasn't even taken shape.
Then what kind of ink is considered
to have taken shape?
Of course, it requires precious materials
and skilled craftsmanship.
When writing,
it should be as smooth
as floating clouds and flying dragons.
I don't understand
any of what you're saying.
Anyway, your father said that,
no matter how beautiful
the ink stick looks on the outside,
or how precious the materials
it's made from,
it is ultimately made for people to use.
So, who uses ink
and what kind of ink they need
are not as complicated as you think.
Just make an ink stick
that is comfortable and handy to use.
Isn't that enough?
Mother,
you really know a lot.
I don't know much.
It's all what your father said.
Eat slowly.
Slowly.
I'm going out for a bit.
Where are you going now?
Come on, madam, take a look at our ink.
Wen.
It's nice and affordable.
I've seen you come here so often
to buy ink for your son.
Why don't you go over there
to buy a good piece?
It's just that my son uses a lot of ink
when he practices writing.
Our family
can't afford to always use good ink.
President Hu,
all the Heads of the Houses
in the ink industry,
this is the Original Intention Ink I made.
One look at this ink,
and you just know
the lampblack was over-burned.
The pounding was also inadequate.
It was made very carelessly.
Indeed.
This ink
neither looks like commercial goods
of high prices,
nor does it have the qualities
of ink to be treasured as an heirloom.
Its production is very ordinary.
In Huizhou, where good ink abounds,
it's really not worth being presented
in public.
Shoddy workmanship!
If I made this ink,
I would be even too embarrassed to enter
the gate of the Literary Association.
I thought
you would ask
Eighth Master Li to help you.
President Hu,
come on, please evaluate this ink.
Having such courage
and showing such sincerity
actually make me think highly of you.
The materials are ordinary,
and the craftsmanship is rough.
It can only be considered a low-grade ink.
It seems that Miss Li Zhen can only...
President Hu,
I gave Zhen the task.
Why
didn't you even show it to me?
Here you are, Third Master.
Zhenniang.
Tell me
why you made an ink stick
with such a simple recipe?
You must have known before making it
that such ink
would not impress the seniors
in the ink trade.
Yes, I know.
Because I couldn't make ink
of better quality
or a more complicated technique.
This is the best ink
I can make for now.
I also thought about
adding precious materials,
but I couldn't blend the ink,
no matter what.
I couldn't meet higher standards,
so I thought
making a simple and useful ink
would also be worthwhile.
This is my original intention.
How could you be so shameless,
directly saying that you couldn't make it?
And "original intention"?
You are just embarrassing yourself!
My abilities fall short.
I admit it.
Everyone here
is a senior in the ink industry.
It's understandable
that you don't think much of this ink.
But to me,
I have done my best.
I can say I have no regret.
Although this ink is of inferior quality,
it has the advantages of being dark enough
and being cheap to produce.
Whether
for keeping accounts in workshops
or for children practicing writing,
it might as well be a better choice.
In this regard,
I believe
I haven't
gone against my original intention,
so I have no regrets.
Now that I know the result today,
I'd like to ask Third Grandfather
to give this ink
to someone who needs it as a gift,
so it will fulfill its value.
It's dark enough.
It's a piece of good ink.
Good ink?
Eldest Young Master Luo,
are you out of your mind?
That is an inferior ink,
and you call it good?
Everything has its suitable function;
materials have their uses;
everything in its right place,
so there is nothing else to be done.
Miss Li Zhen said earlier
that this ink is cheap
and suitable
for accounting and children's writing.
Everyone,
when you first learned to write
as a child,
if given a piece of top-quality ink,
would you be willing to use it?
When our ancestors made
the first piece of ink,
it was to write down
their thoughts and feelings.
How could there be so many rules?
But nothing can be accomplished
without rules.
Without rules, how can we determine
superiority and inferiority?
If we don't tell between good and bad,
what's the point of having
our ink workshops,
having us, and having
this Literary Association?
Hui Ink has been passed down
to the present.
Huizhou ink workshops are ubiquitous.
Aren't we all striving
for perfection?
Yes.
Striving for perfection is
the foundation of ink-making.
I asked the manager of the ink workshop.
He said Miss Li Zhen started learning
ink-making at the ink workshop
only 3 to 5 months ago.
I have a question for you all.
When you had just learned ink-making
for a few months,
could you make
the inferior ink you said?
Yes.
Wensong's words remind me
of when I first entered the ink industry.
Not until I had learned
ink-making for 2 years,
I mean, 2 whole years,
did I make my very first piece of ink.
As for its quality,
it was nothing special.
That being the case,
Miss Li Zhen's ink
must be considered
a piece of good ink for now.
You all have been making ink
for a long time.
Do not forget your original intentions.
Besides,
it's none of your business
whether Miss Li Zhen
makes ink or not.
If I were Miss Li Zhen,
I wouldn't have even bothered
to take this test.
I'd make my own ink.
Why care so much?
You are trying everything to stop her
because you are afraid.
You're afraid that one day,
Miss Li Zhen might
become a master ink-maker
and surpass all of you as a woman,
making you lose face.
You think we'd be afraid of a callow girl?
Ridiculous!
In this case,
there's no need to discuss this further.
Did Zhen really say that?
Word for word.
At her age,
her understanding of ink
is probably...
It's probably even better
than yours or mine.
She asked me to give the ink away.
After careful consideration, I think
the one who needs it most right now
is probably you, Li the Eighth.
Jinshui,
just take her as your apprentice.
Yes,
I know you follow the rules.
You made a vow
that you wouldn't make ink.
But no one ever said that you couldn't
teach others to make ink.
The Literary Association "sealed"
your ink-making hands,
but not your mouth.
Can't you even talk?
Li the Eighth!
Zhen is such a good talent!
What's the harm
in taking her as your apprentice?
Forget the rule of passing it to men
but not women.
Even the Literary Association
has tacitly allowed it!
Jinshui, I'm telling you.
You don't even know how lucky you are!
If Junshan had half of Zhen's talent,
if I had such a brilliant granddaughter,
I'd be willing to stop making ink
for the rest of my life!
Also,
don't you want Li Ink
to have an inheritor?
That's all I want to say.
Think it over yourself.
You stubborn man!
Jingfu.
[Li Jingfu's Tomb]
I'm here to visit you.
This is
the very first ink
your daughter, Zhen, made.
Look,
it's called "Original Intention Ink."
I swore before the Literary Association
that I would never
make ink again.
I have left the ink industry.
But now,
Zhen wants to learn ink-making.
What do you think I should do?
Mother!
Mother, look who's here.
Jinshui.
Seventh Sister-in-law.
Jinshui, what are you doing?
My first kowtow
is for
the ink recipe incident.
I failed your trust, Rujun,
and I am truly
a sinner to Li Ink.
The second kowtow
is for the appreciation
Seventh Brother and you showed me.
I was born in the family's side branch,
with both my parents dead.
Thanks to Seventh Brother, Jingqi,
who strongly recommended me
to the Old Master
and led me into the path of ink-making,
and thanks to you, who always
looked after me like a mother,
I made those achievements later.
I can't
pay you back enough
for this kindness.
Jinshui,
these are all in the past.
Let's leave them behind.
This third kowtow
is for my granddaughter, Zhen.
Rujun,
I once thought Zhen wanted
to learn ink-making
out of momentary anger.
And I didn't want her
to suffer from the smoke and fire.
I didn't expect Zhen
to be genuinely devoted to it,
sticking to her original intention.
Today, I'd like to plead with you, Rujun,
to allow me to teach Zhen ink-making.
There is no need to plead with me.
I've been waiting for you to say this
for ages.
Jinshui, get up. Get up.
Jinshui.
Zhen is gifted
just as you are.
If her talent were to be buried
merely because she is a girl,
wouldn't it be a great pity?
You have my approval.
Thank you, Rujun.
Father, I tried my best.
But I don't regret it.
From now on,
no matter what obstacles lie ahead,
I will never give up on ink-making.
Since I can't learn in the ink workshops,
I'll buy books and learn by myself.
Don't worry, Father.
I will definitely work hard
to make our family live a good life.
Zhen.
Grandfather,
what are you doing?
Zhen,
come over here.
The path of ink-making is
full of hardships and obstacles.
Can you endure them?
I'm willing to endure hardships!
Good.
Founding Master above,
I, Li Jinshui, inheritor
of the Li's Ink-making,
from this moment on,
take Li Zhen
as my apprentice.
I will pass on
the art of ink-making to her.
May you bless her ink-learning journey
to be smooth and successful,
fulfilling her original intention.